Like Zheng

Software Engineer || Product Manager

☑ like@ekil.sh ☐ ekil1100 ☑ ekil1100 in likezheng

About

Hi, my name is Like Zheng. Throughout my 5-year career, I have spent the first 3 years as a software engineer and the latter 2 years primarily working as a product manager, with a decent understanding of UI design. In my spare time, I enjoy writing code and experimenting with new technologies. My expertise leans more towards front-end development as opposed to back-end, and I have a strong focus on user experience, which is why I've taken up learning about product design and UI design. I value teamwork and have successfully built a 6-member front-end team from scratch, fostering an agile culture along the way.

Experience

GreaterHeat Ltd.

Aug 2022 - Present

Product & Community Manager

Remote

After the successful expansion of the company to Singapore, I shifted my focus to product and community management to improve the company's community influence, which included communicating with the Filecoin community and designing product prototypes.

- Designed and developed a Filecoin Sealing-as-a-Service platform.
- Published a weekly newsletter about Filecoin and IPFS within the company with over 100 views. Newsletter was issued for 9 weeks as of this resume update.

ByteArk Tech Ltd.

Aug 2021 - Jul 2022

Product Manager Hangzhou, China

Led a team focused on developing applications based on Filecoin and IPFS.

- Managed a team of 5 people, including 2 Front-End Developers, 2 Back-End Developers, and 1 UI designer.
- Build a cloud storage application based on Filecoin and IPFS.

Muri Tech Ltd.

Mar 2021 - Jul 2021

Front-End Leader Hangzhou, China

Started as a Senior Front-End Engineer and established Git usage guidelines and a design system. Successfully contributed to the team, leading to early regularization and promotion to Front-End Leader.

- Led a team of 8 developers to develop and maintain web applications.
- Refactored codebase to improve code quality, reduce technical debt, and increase site performance by 30%.
- Established Git usage guidelines based on trunk-based development.
- Developed the company's design system.

ByteArk Tech Ltd.

Feb 2019 - Feb 2021

Front-End Leader Hangzhou, China

Started as a Front-End Engineer and was promoted to Front-End Leader upon successful completion of the probation period. Spearheaded the establishment of the Front-End team, developing the team's

development processes and standards.

- Managed a team of 8 developers to develop web applications, mobile apps, and WeChat miniprograms.
- Established the team's development processes and standards, including Git usage guidelines, code review guidelines, and design system.
- Researched Agile development methodologies, implemented best practices to improve team performance, and produced over 10,000 words of documentation.

Ningbo Port Information and Communication Ltd.

Aug 2018 - Jan 2019

Front-end Developer

Ningbo, China

Efficiently developed and meticulously maintained a website for port declaration system using Java and ExtJS.

• Improved developer experience by incorporating polyfills for IE11, increasing browser compatibility and enhancing functionality.

Projects

Pandarua

Aug 2022 - Sep 2022

Product Manager

ByteArk Tech Ltd.

Figma Product Map

Filecoin sealing-as-a-service platform.

• Designed a resource management system to manage the platform's underlying resources and provide a unified interface for the platform.

MePrint Mar 2021 - Jul 2021

Front-End Lead Muri Tech Ltd.

React NextJS React Query Emotion Directus

An Al-powered pattern design platform for the apparel industry.

- Refactored the codebase from UmiJS to NextJS using a progressive model, improving the developer experience (DX) and reducing the bundle size by 10%.
- Managed application state using react-query, reducing bugs in global state management.
- Introduced a headless CMS to manage website content, making it faster and easier for operators to update the site.

Dragonfly Oct 2020 - Nov 2020

Product Manager & Front-End Lead

ByteArk Tech Ltd.

Vue NodeJS Go Powergate IPFS Lotus

A decentralized docker image storage service developed as an entry to the Filecoin Slingshot Program.

- Awarded Phase 1 first prize in the Filecoin Slingshot Program.
- Modified Powergate to support importing cold deals into its database.
- Presented the project at the Closing Ceremony, link available here: https://www.youtube.com/watch? v=qheNJZ1DCIM&t=1390s

Matrix Sep 2019 - Jan 2020

Front-End Lead ByteArk Tech Ltd.

Flutter Taro React Fastlane

Developed a miner management system for Filecoin that includes a mobile app and WeChat mini-program.

- · Built multi-platform mobile applications using Flutter.
- Automated the release process using Fastlane.

Arc Sep 2019 - Jan 2020

Front-End Lead ByteArk Tech Ltd.

TypeScript | React | Rollup | Emotion | Storybook | Jest

A design system focus on accessibility and usability.

- Researched over 10 design systems.
- Developed over 10 components and successfully launched in production.

Education

University of Guelph

Sep 2012 - Dec 2017

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Skills

Front-end Senior JavaScript TypeScript NextJS ReactJS Graphql PostgreSQL Back-end Senior NodeJS Prisma NextJS Graphql Mobile Intermediate Flutter Dart AliCloud **DevOps** Intermediate Docker AWS Vercel Serverless **Project Management** Intermediate Agile Scrum Linear **Design** Intermediate Figma

Languages

Chinese Native speaker English Fluent

https://resume.ekil.io March 16, 2023 at 9:21:48 PM